<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blockchain on IMTI</title>
    <link>https://imti.co/tags/blockchain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blockchain on IMTI</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://imti.co/tags/blockchain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Platform Development with Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://imti.co/kubernetes-platform-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imti.co/kubernetes-platform-book/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been distracted for over a year now, writing a (~500 page) end-to-end tutorial on constructing data-centric platforms with Kubernetes. The book is titled &amp;ldquo;Advanced Platform Development with Kubernetes: Enabling Data Management, the Internet of Things, Blockchain, and Machine Learning&amp;rdquo;
A little more than a year ago, Apress reached out and asked if I would write a book on Kubernetes for them, mirroring the wide range of projects I develop (and write about) for my clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethereum Ethstats</title>
      <link>https://imti.co/ethereum-ethstats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imti.co/ethereum-ethstats/</guid>
      <description>The eth-netstats project provides a great dashboard interface for monitoring the status of an Ethereum Blockchain from the perspective of its nodes. The website https://ethstats.net/ reports statistics from an extensive list of Ethereum nodes on the public Ethereum Blockchain, however, the eth-netstats software that drives https://ethstats.net/ can also be used to monitor a Private Ethereum Blockchchain as I demonstrate in the previous article Deploy a Private Ethereum Blockchain on a Custom Kubernetes Cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethereum Blockchain on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://imti.co/ethereum-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imti.co/ethereum-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Blockchain technologies have been made famous by Cryptocurrencies such as Bitcoin and Ethereum. However, the concepts behind Blockchain are far more reaching than their support for cryptocurrency. Blockchain technologies now support any digital asset, from signal data to complex messaging, to the execution of business logic through code. Blockchain technologies are rapidly forming a new decentralized internet of transactions.
 Support this blog! Buy my new book: Advanced Platform Development with Kubernetes  What You&#39;ll Learn Build data pipelines with MQTT, NiFi, Logstash, MinIO, Hive, Presto, Kafka and Elasticsearch Leverage Serverless ETL with OpenFaaS Explore Blockchain networking with Ethereum Support a multi-tenant Data Science platform with JupyterHub, MLflow and Seldon Core Build a Multi-cloud, Hybrid cluster, securely bridging on-premise and cloud-based Kubernetes nodes    Kubernetes is an efficient and productive platform for the configuration, deployment, and management of private blockchains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain</title>
      <link>https://imti.co/blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imti.co/blockchain/</guid>
      <description>The Internet of Transactions Blockchain may be a recent entry to the technology landscape. However, it has quickly become an essential iteration in the evolution of peer-to-peer communication and distributed computing. Originally developed as a way to protect digital currency, Blockchain technologies now support any digital asset, from signal data to complex messaging, to the execution of business logic through code. Blockchain technologies are rapidly forming a new decentralized internet of transactions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
