<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kubernetes on IMTI</title>
    <link>https://mk2.imti.co/tags/kubernetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kubernetes on IMTI</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mk2.imti.co/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Port Forwarding for Local Development</title>
      <link>https://mk2.imti.co/kubernetes-port-forwarding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mk2.imti.co/kubernetes-port-forwarding/</guid>
      <description>kubefwd helps to enable a seamless and efficient way to develop applications and services on a local workstation. Locally develop applications that intend to interact with other services in a Kubernetes cluster. kubefwd allows applications with connection strings like http://elasticsearch:9200/ or tcp://db:3306 to communicate into the remote cluster. kubefwd can be used to reduce or eliminate the need for local environment specific connection configurations.
Developing services in a Microservices architecture presents local development challenges, especially when the service you are developing needs to interact with a mixture of other services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FaaS on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://mk2.imti.co/fass-kubeless-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mk2.imti.co/fass-kubeless-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>FaaS or Function as a Service also known as Serverless computing implementations are gaining popularity. Discussed often are the cost savings and each implementations relationship to the physical and network architecture of a specific platform or vendor. While many of the cost and infrastructure advantages of FaaS are compelling, its only one of many advantages. Below, I hope to demonstrate how easy it is to develop and deploy FaaS components into a custom Kubernetes cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helm on Custom Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://mk2.imti.co/helm-on-custom-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mk2.imti.co/helm-on-custom-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Helm is the official package manager for Kubernetes. If you are looking to start using Helm or want to test its capabilities, I suggest you set up a Production Hobby Cluster. This article is a continuation of the Production Hobby Cluster configuration but should be entirely useful on its own.
 From https://github.com/kubernetes/helm - Helm has two parts: a client (helm) and a server (tiller) - Tiller runs inside of your Kubernetes cluster and manages releases (installations) of your charts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Custom Upstream DNS</title>
      <link>https://mk2.imti.co/kubernetes-custom-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mk2.imti.co/kubernetes-custom-dns/</guid>
      <description>Customize the Upstream Nameservers used by kube-dns by Pods when looking up external hostnames from within a Kubernetes cluster. I found that adding custom Upstream Nameservers to my kube-dns solved many issues encountered in in the past with external hostname resolution on individual Pods.
If you want to experiment on a production-like cluster, I suggest reading my article &amp;ldquo;Production Hobby Cluster&amp;rdquo; for a guide on setting up a fun, cheap-yet-robust experimental cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ingress on Custom Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://mk2.imti.co/web-cluster-ingress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mk2.imti.co/web-cluster-ingress/</guid>
      <description>There are more than a handful of ways to set up port 80 and 443 web ingress on a custom Kubernetes cluster. Specifically a bare metal cluster. If you are looking to experiment or learn on a non-production cluster, but something more true to production than minikube, I suggest you check out my previous article Production Hobby Cluster, a step-by-step guide for setting up a custom production capable Kubernetes cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kubectl Context Multiple Clusters</title>
      <link>https://mk2.imti.co/kubectl-remote-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mk2.imti.co/kubectl-remote-context/</guid>
      <description>I use a few Kubernetes clusters on a daily basis, and I use kubectl to access and configure them from my workstation. There are dozens of ways to configure kubectl however I find the following method the easiest for me to manage and not make a mess.
I also set up test clusters from time-to-time, and so keeping my configs organized is, so I don&amp;rsquo;t confuse myself or make a mess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubectl x509 Unable to Connect</title>
      <link>https://mk2.imti.co/kubectl-remote-x509-valid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mk2.imti.co/kubectl-remote-x509-valid/</guid>
      <description>Just set up a brand new cluster? Changed the domain or IP of your admin node? Then you may have encountered the error Unable to connect to the server: x509: certificate is valid for &amp;hellip;. The following is a fix for this common issue. However, there are often other reasons to rebuild your cluster cert, and it&amp;rsquo;s relatively easy.
TL;DR: &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t care about the fix I need to remote control my cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Production Hobby Cluster</title>
      <link>https://mk2.imti.co/hobby-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mk2.imti.co/hobby-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Setting up a production-grade Kubernetes cluster can be done on a hobby budget, and if this is true why mess around with a lesser grade. If you are investing time to learn distributed cloud computing or microservices, is the distance between $0 and 15 dollars a month worth the time in translating best practices? Kubernetes is designed to host production applications. My personal web applications may only be hobbies, but they might as well be production grade hobbies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes - 413 Request Entity Too Large</title>
      <link>https://mk2.imti.co/413-request-entity-too-large/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mk2.imti.co/413-request-entity-too-large/</guid>
      <description>When setting up nginx ingress on Kubernetes for a private Docker Registry, I ran into an error when trying to push an image to it.
Error parsing HTTP response: invalid character &#39;&amp;lt;&#39; looking for beginning of value: &amp;quot;&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;413 Request Entity Too Large&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;body bgcolor=\&amp;quot;white\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;center&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;413 Request Entity Too Large&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/center&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;hr&amp;gt;&amp;lt;center&amp;gt;nginx/1.9.14&amp;lt;/center&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;\r\n&amp;quot;  The &amp;ldquo;413 Request Entity Too Large&amp;rdquo; error is something many accustomed to running nginx as a standard web server/proxy. nginx is configured to restrict the size of files it will allow over a post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Remote Control</title>
      <link>https://mk2.imti.co/kubectl-remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mk2.imti.co/kubectl-remote/</guid>
      <description>I use Minikube to run a local Kubernetes single node cluster (cluster?). However, I also work with a custom production cluster for work. This cluster consists of development and production nodes. I often need to switch between working on my local Minikube and the online Kubernetes cluster.
TIP: Visit the kubectl Cheat Sheet often.
The default configuration kubectl is stored in ~/.kube/config and if you have Minikube installed, it added the context minikube to your config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microservices &amp; Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://mk2.imti.co/microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mk2.imti.co/microservices/</guid>
      <description>The following is a collection of articles, videos, and notes on Microservices. The Microservices architecture is a variant of the service-oriented architecture, a collection of loosely coupled services.
Articles  Background concept - &amp;ldquo;Open Data: Small Pieces Loosely Joined&amp;rdquo;, Tim O’Reilly Modern software design problems and solutions - &amp;ldquo;12-Fractured Apps&amp;rdquo;, Kelsey Hightower (SysAdmin @ Google) 12-Factor Defined - &amp;ldquo;The 12-Factor App&amp;rdquo;, Adam Wiggins Pros and Cons of Microservices - &amp;ldquo;Microservices&amp;rdquo; and Microservice Trade-Offs, Martin Fowler &amp;ldquo;What are containers and why do you need them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Overview</title>
      <link>https://mk2.imti.co/kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mk2.imti.co/kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Getting started with Kubernetes for local development. I develop on a Mac however much of this is easily translated to windows.
The following is primarily a getting started guide wrapped around my personal development notes. This set of notes are specifically for my co-workers in helping them get up to speed quickly. If you see an error feel free to make a pull request or just add an issue.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>