<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on IMTI</title>
    <link>https://imti.co/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on IMTI</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://imti.co/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear Algebra: Vectors</title>
      <link>https://imti.co/linear-algebra-vectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imti.co/linear-algebra-vectors/</guid>
      <description>This article on vectors is part of an ongoing crash course on linear algebra programming, demonstrating concepts and implementations in Python. The following examples will demonstrate some of the algebraic and geometric interpretations of a vector using Python. A vector is an ordered list of numbers, represented in row or column form.
This small series of articles on linear algebra is meant to help you prepare for learning the deeper concepts related to Machine Learning and math that drives the higher level abstractions provided many of the libraries available today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FaaS on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://imti.co/fass-kubeless-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imti.co/fass-kubeless-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>FaaS or Function as a Service also known as Serverless computing implementations are gaining popularity. Discussed often are the cost savings and each implementations relationship to the physical and network architecture of a specific platform or vendor. While many of the cost and infrastructure advantages of FaaS are compelling, its only one of many advantages. Below, I hope to demonstrate how easy it is to develop and deploy FaaS components into a custom Kubernetes cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Data Essentials - Matplotlib and Seaborn</title>
      <link>https://imti.co/python-data-essentials-matplotlib-seaborn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imti.co/python-data-essentials-matplotlib-seaborn/</guid>
      <description>There is an overwhelming number of options for developers needing to provide data visualization. The most popular library for data visualization in Python is Matplotlib, and built directly on top of Matplotlib is Seaborn. The Seaborn library is &amp;ldquo;tightly integrated with the PyData stack, including support for numpy and pandas data structures and statistical routines from scipy and statsmodels.&amp;rdquo;
This article is only intended to get you started with Matplotlib and Seaborn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Data Essentials - Pandas</title>
      <link>https://imti.co/python-data-essentials-pandas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imti.co/python-data-essentials-pandas/</guid>
      <description>Pandas bring Python a data type equivalent to super-charged spreadsheets. Pandas add two highly expressive data structures to Python, Series and DataFrame. Pandas Series and DataFrames provide a performant analysis and manipulation of “relational” or “labeled” data similar to relational database tables like MySQL or the rows and columns of Excel. Pandas are great for working with time series data as well as arbitrary matrix data, and unlabeled data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Data Essentials - Numpy</title>
      <link>https://imti.co/python-data-essentials-numpy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imti.co/python-data-essentials-numpy/</guid>
      <description>Python is one of The Most Popular Languages for Data Science, and because of this adoption by the data science community, we have libraries like NumPy, Pandas and Matplotlib. NumPy at it&amp;rsquo;s core provides a powerful N-dimensional array objects in which we can perform linear algebra, Pandas give us data structures and data analysis tools, similar to working with a specialized database or powerful spreadsheets and finally Matplotlib to generate plots, histograms, power spectra, bar charts, error charts and scatterplots to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential Python 3</title>
      <link>https://imti.co/essential-python3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imti.co/essential-python3/</guid>
      <description>This article is a quick tour of basic Python 3 syntax, components and structure. I intend to balance a cheat sheet format with hello world style boilerplate. If you are already a software developer and need a quick refresh on Python then I hope you benefit from my notes below.
I am a professional software developer for a software development company, and for that reason, I work with a lot of languages, expert in some, and ok in others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>